[Music]
Do you spend much of your time filling
out records in Business Central? We all
know that data entry is tedious. It can
be errorprone and we'd much rather spend
time on higher value tasks like making
datadriven decisions. Uh but Copilot
luckily makes every day a little bit
easier with the autofill feature. uh it
suggests appropriate field values. So
all you need to do is choose to keep
them. And now in this wave, it also
searches the web on your behalf to help
you fill out contact details such as
addresses or other fields where you
typically browse to an answer.
And with Copilot connected to the web,
you no longer need to switch apps just
to go and browse around and come back
again just to complete those data entry
tasks. My name is Mike and here's a
4-minute tour of Copilot's autofill
feature and how we've enhanced this in
2025 release wave 2. So, let's imagine
that I'm adding swimming gear to my
product catalog and I want to register
my reseller in Business Central. I'll
create a new vendor
and I'll name that Adventure Works.
And now I know this customer is from
Washington State, but I really don't
know the other details here. So now I'm
going to use the sparkle icon or the alt
I shortcut to ask copilot for
assistance. Copilot is now searching the
web on my behalf searching for adventure
works and it's using Microsoft Bing
search to find that information and
present it right here as a suggestion
for me inside Business Central.
And there we go. Not only has it
suggested the zip code for this
customer, but it's also provided the
address, the city, the phone number, the
email and homepage. Now, the first thing
I want to do is make sure that it's
found the right adventure works. There
may be many of those on the internet and
the homepage looks right,
adventure-works.com.
Um, I can also see how Copilot came up
with each of these suggestions. For
example, for the city here, I can use
the info tip to see that Copilot used a
web search and the city is specified in
the retail store address for Adventure
Works. Uh, it also provides me with a
link that I can use to go straight to
that grounding data. Where was this
information taken from? It was taken
from adventureworks.com.
I'm just going to click that and go to
Adventure Works. And let me just check
that this is the right one. Yes, this is
the one that sells our swimming gear
that we're looking for. And there's the
snorkel and dive products that I will
soon be reselling in my company.
Fantastic. So, Copilot has found the
right one. Now, um here you want to
check that it's picked up the right
address and this is roughly the right
information you're looking for. And you
can choose to keep all of that with one
click by saying keep all. The moment you
do that, Business Center will validate
each of those fields to maintain the
integrity of your data. Of course, now
Copilot's autofill can do a lot more.
For example, if I need help with filling
some more fields, I can again ask
Copilot for assistance. It may not
search the web for certain information.
It may look at, for example, what have
you recently set for your responsibility
center or what is the most common
responsibility center that I use in
Business Central and provide those
suggestions.
Now, how does Copilot actually connect
to the web? So, you want to make sure
that administrators go to the Copilot
and agent capabilities page. This is
where you get control and transparency
of all your C-pilot features and your
agents. And here, make sure you've
enabled enable Bing search. Uh, make
sure you read sort of which features
actually use Bing search to have Copilot
enhance its results of the web. Um
there's additional links you can follow
and once you enable this, Copilot will
now be able to provide those suggestions
also for contact details. All right,
this is when you go try out the public
preview view of C-Pilot's autofill
feature uh on your favorite pages. Uh in
fact, autofill is available in all
Business Central countries in all
languages and on all types of
environments. Uh we've assessed the
quality of language in English and we're
looking forward to adding support for
many more languages later on in this
wave. Now, make sure you try out some of
the new things as well. Uh, find address
fields, try it out on other fields, uh,
such as tax registration numbers,
product codes. A lot of those can be
found on the web as well. Let Copilot
search the web for you. Uh, try out the
keyboard experience as well. Use the Alt
I shortcut to ask Copilot to autofill
the fields in that group of fields and
use the Alt up to toggle between tool
tips, thoseformational tips about where
Copilot got that information and so on.
And if you need more tips, I've dropped
a link uh below this video where you can
learn about how to use this feature, but
also for developers. How can developers
influence the output of Copilot for
their custom fields and their custom
pages as well. Now, autofill is
Copilot's new superpower in Business
Central. It makes everyday data entry a
little bit lighter. And we're looking
forward to your feedback about how this
works for you on your fields. And we
want to really improve this to a point
where autofill works on more fields with
more intelligent suggestions as well.
All right. Well, if you enjoyed this
video, make sure you like and subscribe.
You'll get many more of these. Uh I look
forward to seeing you in the next video
and thanks for watching.